<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?><TEXTBOOK><TOPIC><TITLE>Infrastructure as a service</TITLE><Definition>ObjectWeb merged with Orientware to create OW2. OW2 is devoted to developing distributed infrastructure software able to interconnect systems that are heterogeneous by nature. To this end the software developed by OW2 complies with open standards established by independent bodies such as JCP OMG or OSGi and grants open access to the source code by means of open source licenses. OW2 claims that the open source approach guarantees the best possible level of compliance with standards. The aim of the consortium is promoting the dialogue between technology suppliers and user companies in order to foster the emergence of an offering of professional solutions based on open source infrastructure software together with the required services such as training advice and maintenance.This subject introduces students to cloud computing fundamentals case studies and their applications for the development of software as a service in the cloud. Following a brief introduction to cloud computing the cloud architecture infrastructure as a service platform as a service software as a service SaaS virtualisation and multi tenancy features are explained. The theoretical discussion of these topics is supplemented with practical introductory exercises for SaaS development in the cloud</Definition></TOPIC><TOPIC><TITLE>Software as a service</TITLE><Definition>Sify rated at Top 25 Cloud Computing Companies in India as the most innovative and promising Cloud Service Provider by Silicon India. Sify rated at Top 25 Cloud Computing Companies in India as the most innovative and promising Cloud Service Provider by Silicon India. Sify rated at Top 25 Cloud Computing Companies in India as the most innovative and promising Cloud Service Provider by Silicon India. Sify rated at Top 25 Cloud Computing Companies in India as the most innovative and promising Cloud Service Provider by Silicon India. Sify rated at Top 25 Cloud Computing Companies in India as the most innovative and promising Cloud Service Provider by Silicon India.According to a September 2009 Gartner Group report 3 Force.com had over 1 000 customer accounts in addition to tens of thousands that used Force.com in conjunction with Salesforce. Force</Definition></TOPIC><TOPIC><TITLE>Platform as a service</TITLE><Definition>Sify rated at Top 25 Cloud Computing Companies in India as the most innovative and promising Cloud Service Provider by Silicon India. Sify rated at Top 25 Cloud Computing Companies in India as the most innovative and promising Cloud Service Provider by Silicon India. Sify rated at Top 25 Cloud Computing Companies in India as the most innovative and promising Cloud Service Provider by Silicon India. Sify rated at Top 25 Cloud Computing Companies in India as the most innovative and promising Cloud Service Provider by Silicon India. Sify rated at Top 25 Cloud Computing Companies in India as the most innovative and promising Cloud Service Provider by Silicon India.Platform as a Service PaaS is a delivery of a computing platform over the web. PaaS enables you to create web applications quickly without the cost and complexity of buying and managing the underlying software hardware. PaaS provides all the facilities required to support the complete life cycle of building and delivering web applications entirely on the web. As Platform as a Service PaaS is available as a service the developer and ISV s get full control of the application development and deployment. PaaS enables developers and ISV s to create custom web applications and deliver it quickly as many of the hassles like setting up hosting servers databases user interaction process and frameworks are prepackaged</Definition></TOPIC></TEXTBOOK>
