<TEXTBOOK><TOPIC><TITLE>Microprocessor</TITLE><DEFINITION>To understand how a microprocessor works it is helpful to look inside and learn about the logic used to create one.The Intel 4004 is generally regarded as the first commercially available microprocessor 13 14 and cost 60. 15 The first known advertisement for the 4004 is dated November 15 1971 and appeared in Electronic News . 16 The project that produced the 4004 originated in 1969 when Busicom a Japanese calculator manufacturer asked Intel to build a chipset for high performance desktop calculators. Busicom s original design called for a programmable chip set consisting of seven different chips. Three of the chips were to make a special purpose CPU with its program stored in ROM and its data stored in shift register read write memory.As a smart shopper you may be hunting for laptop deals but you may want to check several features on laptops for sale that can affect the quality of these cheap computers. 16 The project that produced the 4004 originated in 1969 when Busicom a Japanese calculator manufacturer asked Intel to build a chipset for high performance desktop calculators. Busicom s original design called for a programmable chip set consisting of seven different chips. Three of the chips were to make a special purpose CPU with its program stored in ROM and its data stored in shift register read write memory. Based on the instructions a microprocessor does three basic things Using its ALU Arithmetic Logic Unit a microprocessor can perform mathematical operations like addition subtraction multiplication and division. 16 The project that produced the 4004 originated in 1969 when Busicom a Japanese calculator manufacturer asked Intel to build a chipset for high performance desktop calculators. Busicom s original design called for a programmable chip set consisting of seven different chips. Three of the chips were to make a special purpose CPU with its program stored in ROM and its data stored in shift register read write memory.As a smart shopper you may be hunting for laptop deals but you may want to check several features on laptops for sale that can affect the quality of these cheap computers. 16 The project that produced the 4004 originated in 1969 when Busicom a Japanese calculator manufacturer asked Intel to build a chipset for high performance desktop calculators. Busicom s original design called for a programmable chip set consisting of seven different chips. Three of the chips were to make a special purpose CPU with its program stored in ROM and its data stored in shift register read write memory. A microprocessor executes a collection of machine instructions that tell the processor what to do. Based on the instructions a microprocessor does three basic things Using its ALU Arithmetic Logic Unit a microprocessor can perform mathematical operations like addition subtraction multiplication and division. 16 The project that produced the 4004 originated in 1969 when Busicom a Japanese calculator manufacturer asked Intel to build a chipset for high performance desktop calculators. Busicom s original design called for a programmable chip set consisting of seven different chips. Three of the chips were to make a special purpose CPU with its program stored in ROM and its data stored in shift register read write memory.As a smart shopper you may be hunting for laptop deals but you may want to check several features on laptops for sale that can affect the quality of these cheap computers. 16 The project that produced the 4004 originated in 1969 when Busicom a Japanese calculator manufacturer asked Intel to build a chipset for high performance desktop calculators. Busicom s original design called for a programmable chip set consisting of seven different chips. Three of the chips were to make a special purpose CPU with its program stored in ROM and its data stored in shift register read write memory. In the process you can also learn about assembly language the native language of a microprocessor and many of the things that engineers can do to boost the speed of a processor. A microprocessor executes a collection of machine instructions that tell the processor what to do. Based on the instructions a microprocessor does three basic things Using its ALU Arithmetic Logic Unit a microprocessor can perform mathematical operations like addition subtraction multiplication and division. 16 The project that produced the 4004 originated in 1969 when Busicom a Japanese calculator manufacturer asked Intel to build a chipset for high performance desktop calculators. Busicom s original design called for a programmable chip set consisting of seven different chips. Three of the chips were to make a special purpose CPU with its program stored in ROM and its data stored in shift register read write memory.As a smart shopper you may be hunting for laptop deals but you may want to check several features on laptops for sale that can affect the quality of these cheap computers. 16 The project that produced the 4004 originated in 1969 when Busicom a Japanese calculator manufacturer asked Intel to build a chipset for high performance desktop calculators. Busicom s original design called for a programmable chip set consisting of seven different chips. Three of the chips were to make a special purpose CPU with its program stored in ROM and its data stored in shift register read write memory</DEFINITION></TOPIC><TOPIC><TITLE>Laptop</TITLE><DEFINITION>As a smart shopper you may be hunting for laptop deals but you may want to check several features on laptops for sale that can affect the quality of these cheap computers. Once you know which laptop features to check you ll know whether or not you re getting a truly good deal. A laptop computer is a perfect solution for the computer user on the go. Comparing laptop computers can be frustrating and time consuming if you aren t aware of which features to look out for. DELL PREFERRED ACCOUNT DPA Offered to U. residents by WebBank who determines qualifications for and terms of credit. Promotion eligibility varies and is determined by WebBank. Taxes shipping and other charges are extra and vary. Hewlett Packard Development Company L. DELL PREFERRED ACCOUNT DPA Offered to U. residents by WebBank who determines qualifications for and terms of credit. Promotion eligibility varies and is determined by WebBank. Taxes shipping and other charges are extra and vary</DEFINITION></TOPIC></TEXTBOOK>
